Phil Tipping – CV

7 Criddle Avenue
Banwell
North Somerset
BS29 6LA
philtipping3110@gmail.com
07496170611

Personal

I am a confident, self-motivated person who is trustworthy and initiative-taking. With my employment history I deliver a high level of customer service working both independently and as part of a team.

With a professional approach to work, a good problem solver, and someone who is comfortable conversing with all types of people. I also enjoy dealing with technology, software, and other forms of electronics at home and within work. I have good written and strong communication skills and the ability to prioritise work effectively under strict deadlines. I enjoy new challenges, constantly learning within my employment and outside of work.

When I am outside of work, I enjoy socialising and regularly going to the gym. Fitness is an important factor in my life and doing sports such as football and surfing. Music is also a strong passion of mine and I have played for over 14 years and I continue to play guitar and compose music in my free time.

Work Experience

Support Analyst III – MRI Software (Remote) April 2023 to present

PropTech group was purchased by MRI Software. My roles remain the same as the below however I am now in a bigger team of people who look after multiple types of software. My job title has been changed to Support Analyst III and I still provide all support and customer care for VaultEA and MRI Inspect. Both software's support estate agencies within the UK. Over these two programmes, I look after about 300 offices and all their users and help them with training, issues, and general support. I have had to adapt to lots of changes within my role such as new third party systems and processes.

Includes the use of:

- Mircosoft Teams/Office programmes
- Jira
- Workday
- Zendesk
- Google/Gsuite
- CRMs

Customer Support Advisor / Client Services Team Leader - ClientVault - United Kingdom - (Remote) August 2020 to April 2023

Part of PTG (PropTech Group), we supply multiple products that deal with all areas of the estate agency business. My job role consists of supporting all our customers via email, ticketing systems and telephone. This relates to all types of queries they may have with the software we provide to them, including training our customers in certain areas. Due to my previous background in estate agency, I have been able to help improve the software to make our customers lives as easy as possible and make sure the company can become more successful here in the UK. I've been able to adapt to all types of situations due to the nature of the job and work within my own initiative to get tasks completed by myself when needed. I now run all of the support for two software systems that we provide and have had to do this role alone for some time.

Main Skills Required:

- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Customer Service
- Customer Interaction
- Deadlines / Time Management
- Monitoring Requests
- Usage of multiple online systems Microsoft/Google/Slack/Monday/Zendesk/Zoom
- Delegation of work
- Working alone and in a small team
- Training Clients

Sales Negotiator - Palmer Snell Estate Agents - Worle/Weston-super-Mare January 2018 to July 2020

I joined Palmer Snell at the start of 2018. Going into a completely different type of career was exciting for me and I have seen the benefits from working for a large estate agency group. It has taught me a lot in learning how to sell efficiently and always behave in a professional manner with customers as well as creating good relationships with the public. Building relationships is an important part of my work and I really enjoy seeing people benefit from the service I have provided them.

Working in a sales environment has given me a high sense of drive to achieve goals and be my best. I was targeted on a daily to monthly basis and must keep on top of these targets constantly. I communicate with clients via the telephone and email every day making me very confident with all types of people and very comfortable using a computer along with various programmes. I have also been on training courses for property listing and sales progression. We do regularly get online refresher courses that we have to complete such as GDPR and the Estate Agency Act. I really enjoyed working in this industry and feel that all the opportunities I have been given to progress and develop will allow me to adapt to different possibilities in the future.

Main Skills Required:

- Negotiation
- Sales
- Sale Progression
- Hitting Targets
- Communication
- Interacting with the public
- Email and telephone skills
- Diary management

Associate / Team Leader - Tk Maxx October 2013 to December 2017

I joined Tk Maxx as one of thirty members of staff that were employed on a temporary contract in the lead up to the Christmas period. Like many of the other 'temps', my intention was to sufficiently impress my new employer in order to secure a permanent position. Towards the end of January, they offered 4 permanent placements to which I was offered and then was chosen to carry on my time there. Tk Maxx provided me with training in various areas of retail. This has allowed me to develop various skills from stock control whilst handling deliveries to my customer service skills whilst working on the checkout. Working here has expanded my customer service skills, as I spent a lot of timeserving and interacting with customers on a day to day basis. This has helped my confidence when speaking to members of the public and ensuring I satisfy their needs. I then progressed on to training to be a team leader which I have had to work very hard for. Part of this needed me to take part in various areas of training to help improve my knowledge and skills. These included Time Management, Customer Service, Adapting to Change and Managing people, along with many other areas. I feel that doing this has helped me develop as a person, enabled me to grow and make me much more aware and confident in being in a customer-based job.

Main Skills Required:

- Customer Service
- Team leader
- Working as a team
- Resilience
- Managing People
- Time management

Other Work Experience

Bartender – Gold Lion Pub, Worle, Weston-super-Mare Paper Round Volunteering work at Weston Hospice Care

Education

Currently Studying Diploma in Full Stack Web Development Code institute / Learning People Oct 2023 - Present (1 Year Course - finishing Oct 2024)

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Python

Consists of 5 Portfolio Projects.

A-Level or equivalent in Music Performance- Graded ABB (3 A levels) Weston University Campus September 2013 to May 2016

GCSE or equivalent in English/Maths/Science/IT/Music/Art/Spanish Worle Community School September 2006 to June 2012

References

Daniel Livesey Manager Palmer Snell Estate Agents 01934 660198

Lisa Sheppard Manager VaultEA – ClientVault UK Pty Ltd lisa@vaultea.co.uk 07788438441